Kyle Romero

kgromero@gmail.com (281) 857-9006 https://kgromero.com

Hello! My name is Kyle Romero. I am a senior software development manager, with full-stack technical lead experience, living in Jersey City, NJ. I have a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering from Texas Tech University, and have worked in the IT field since 2007 focused on internal software development. Currently, I am a manager of operations technology, and previously was a team lead and senior developer at Worldwide Machinery, and a technical lead at HP. I have extensive knowledge of all aspects of a successful software project, and have used many different technologies and methodologies over the years.

Linkedin kyleromero **Github** romero927

EXPERIENCE

InfraSource, A Quanta Services Company (part of MEARS Group)

Senior Manager - Operations Technology Oct 2017 - Present

Construction and Professional Services (Natural Gas, Oil, and Electric Power Industry)

- Direct-Report to CIO of MEARS Group, helping to define and drive software development strategy
- Promoted from Operations Technology Manager after 2.5 years of successful software delivery
- Head of Software Development for InfraSource
- Architect and explore new technology solutions (focused on digital transformation)
- Build out company's internal tools using appropriate technologies
- Manage a team of internal and external developers and project managers
- Coordinate external and internal teams using Agile processes
- Travel as needed to various sites around US to deploy new software solutions and manage IT relationship with other groups
- Interface between technical and non-technical personnel; help to bridge the communication gap
- Provide consultation on software development initiatives across MEARS Group
- Create learning curriculum for new developers and provide training / KT sessions
- Manage DevOps, CICD, and PM processes
- Administration of various systems including: Windows Servers, Azure, Azure DevOps, and Sharepoint Online
- Prototyping / hands-on exploration of new technologies
- <REPLACE WITH TABLE OF TECH HERE>

Worldwide Machinery

Team Lead / Senior Software Developer Apr 2016 - Oct 2017

Heavy Machinery Rental and Sales Company

- Manage project workflow using Agile Scrum methodology
- Manage junior developers' workloads
- Develop modern ASP.NET MVC WebAPI

- Develop modern Mobile-first Web Application using React, Redux, Typescript (ES6), Node.js + Express + NPM, Babel, Webpack, and SASS
- Maintain legacy ERP application using .NET Winforms (C#, MS SQL)
- Implement and Maintain Project and DevOps Processes using: JIRA, Bitbucket (GIT), TeamCity, Trello,
 Slack, Lucidcharts
- Proactively identify process improvements, as well as project opportunities
- Maintain / troubleshoot hardware infrastructure as needed (Windows / Ubuntu Servers)
- <REPLACE WITH TABLE OF TECH HERE>

HP Inc.

Technical Lead (IT Developer / Engineer III) Dec 2013 - Feb 2016

Consumer IT Products

- Led development team working on enterprise level product quality / escalation management tool.
- Helped manage both onshore and offshore, full time and contingent developers.
- Helped to define and improve processes used on project, including development of a customized disciplined agile methodology and setting project timelines.
- Administered Team Foundation Server (source and requirements).
- Managed quality control and workloads for developers on project.
- Managed release process for tool.
- Worked with business to define requirements and develop architecture for project.
- Familiar with all aspects of project, from both technical and business standpoints.
- While working on .NET Applications, received exposure to Big Data technologies, such as Hadoop and HP Vertica, as well as Dashboarding Technologies, such as Qlikview and Tableau.
- During the year 2015, led team to successfully complete clone of our systems to be used on both sides of HP after the company split into two.
- <REPLACE WITH TABLE OF TECH HERE>

HP

Software Developer (IT Developer / Engineer II) Nov 2011 - Dec 2013

- Worked on ASP.NET Web applications incorporating a 3-Tier approach.
- Did work on all three tiers (MS SQL Database, VB.NET Middle tier object libraries, and ASP.NET + jQueryUI frontend).
- Project was managed using Agile Scrum methodology (Received Certified Scrum Master certification 2012).
- Source control system was Team Foundation Server.
- <REPLACE WITH TABLE OF TECH HERE>

X-Fab Texas, Inc.

Software / Systems Engineer Dec 2009 - Nov 2011

Pure-play Semiconductor Foundry

- Development of ASP.NET/C# Web applications to serve as frontends for MSSQL databases.
- Developed .NET Web / Console / Winforms Applications.
- Involved in Database Design. Administered Windows and Linux servers.
- Designed Shell / Batch scripts. Developed C++ console applications.

- Deployed machine monitoring system. Developed Inventory tracking system.
- Deployed Documentation system to sites globally.
- <REPLACE WITH TABLE OF TECH HERE>

X-Fab Texas, Inc.

IT Intern May 2007 - Dec 2009

Internship between TTU EE Department and X-Fab, Texas

- Developed various internal software projects, including statistical analysis programs, format conversion software, and .NET web applications.
- <REPLACE WITH TABLE OF TECH HERE>

EDUCATION

Texas Tech University

Aug 2005 - Dec 2009 Bachelor of Science - Computer Engineering GPA: 2.944

REFERENCES

— Available Upon Request